Reading
The Band That Wasn't
Have you ever wanted to be part of a band as a famous singer or musician?
Have you ever dreamed of playing in front of thousands of people at a concert,
at which everyone is clapping and appreciating your music?
To be honest, a lot of people attach great importance to becoming rich
and famous.
But just how do people form a band?
Many musicians meet and form a band because they like to write
and play their own music.
Sometimes they may play to passers-by in the street or subway
so that they can earn some extra money for themselves or to pay
for their instruments.
Later they may give performances in pubs or clubs,
for which they are paid in cash.
Of course they hope to make records in a studio and sell millions of copies to become millionaires!
However, there was one band that started in a different way.
The musicians were to play jokes on each other as well as play music,
most of which was based loosely on the Beatles.
The TV organizers had planned to find four musicians who could act as well as sing.
They put an advertisement in a newspaper looking for rock musicians,
but they could only find one who was good enough.
They had to use actors for the other three members of the band.
As some of these actors could not sing well enough,
they had to rely on other musicians to help them.
So during the broadcasts they just pretended to sing.
Anyhow their performances were humorous enough to be copied by other groups.
They were so popular that their fans formed clubs in order to get more familiar
with them.
Then they produced their own records and started touring and playing their own music.
In the USA they became even more popular than the Beatles and sold even more records.
They produced a new record in 1996,
with which they celebrated their former time as a real band.